<!DOCTYPE html>
<html>
<head>
  <meta charset="utf-8">
  <meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="IE=edge">
  <meta name="description" content="A Math / CS student at CMU">
  <meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0">
  <title>Evan Bergeron</title>
  <link rel="stylesheet" href="css/normalize.css">
  <link rel="stylesheet" href="css/syntax.css">
  <link rel="stylesheet" href="css/solo.css">

</head>
<body>
  <div class="container">
    <h1><a href="./">Hi, I'm Evan</a></h1>
    <?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Evan Bergeron</title>
 <link href="atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href=""/>
 <updated>2015-03-29T02:28:13-05:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Some Useful Key Remappings</title>
   <link href="/2014/09/27/Some-Useful-Key-Remaps.html"/>
   <updated>2014-09-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/09/27/Some-Useful-Key-Remaps</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Caps-Lock -&amp;gt; Escape and Shift keys when tapped -&amp;gt; left and right parens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these were inspired by Steve Losh’s infamous &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevelosh.com/blog/2012/10/a-modern-space-cadet/&quot;&gt;A Modern Space Cadet&lt;/a&gt; article. Months ago I followed the instructions to remap my caps-lock key and shift keys as instructed. I lived happily for many months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I switched to linux and was unable to find similar instructions for linux. I found a couple lone souls out there trying to remap keys using xmodmap. But xmodmap (as far as I can tell) can’t tell how long you hold down the keys for. I found a couple of hacks, but nothing worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alols/xcape&quot;&gt;xcape&lt;/a&gt;. I cloned from github and entered&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
./xcape -e &#39;Shift_L=Shift_L|parenleft&#39;
./xcape -e &#39;Shift_R=Shift_R|parenright&#39;
./xcape -e &#39;Caps_Lock=Escape&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viola. My main complaint about switching to linux was rectified. Hopefully this helps someone else out there as well :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Evan&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Boolean Expressions and Their Value</title>
   <link href="/2014/08/12/boolean-expressions-and-their-value.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/08/12/boolean-expressions-and-their-value</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Edsger Dijkstra has suggested that the programming language ALGOL 60 was the first programming language to make the distinction that a boolean expression wasn’t simply something that was “right” or “wrong,” but that it had a value - true or false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How great that step was I learned from my mother’s reaction. She was a gifted mathematician, but she could not make that step. For her, “three plus five is ten” was not a complicated way of saying “false”; it was just wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distinction is analogous to the difference between the statements “All blondes are dumb” and “What if all blondes were dumb?” It’s about the context and usage. The first statement, in the case that it’s false, has no real value. But the second statement’s merit is not dependent on its truth value: it’s useful regardless of whether it’s true or false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in programming, we may have some proposition and might want to do different things if said proposition is true or false. It’s not that we’re hell-bent on the fact that x + y == z, we just want to know what to do in either situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to think that booleans weren’t always first-class citizens. Not only in programming and computer science, but mathematically as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In modern discrete math classes, we are taught about quantified boolean formula statements that hold the value true or false. We become accustomed to assigning truth values to these statements. It’s odd that we didn’t always view them in that light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same interview as the above quote, Dijkstra claims that “computing science started with ALGOL 60.” Recently reading about &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PSPACE&quot;&gt;PSPACE&lt;/a&gt; and its canonical representative, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantified_Boolean_formula_problem&quot;&gt;TQBF&lt;/a&gt;, I’m inclined to agree.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World!</title>
   <link href="/2014/08/11/hello-world.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/08/11/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Howdy! Hoping to post fun and interesting math / cs content here in the future! Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Evan&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>

  </div>

</body>
</html>
